Dario Di Nucci – February 2019 Short CV – Including Summary of Publications

Personal Data

Home address: Louis Hapstraat 198, 1040 Brussels, Belgium, +32 486 13 99 51

Office address: Pleinlaan 2, 1050 Brussel, Belgium

Email: dario.di.nucci@vub.be
Website: http://dardin88.github.io

Languages: Italian (native), English (High B2)

Miscellaneous: Sex: Male, Nationality: Italian, Age: 30, born on 03/09/1988 in Isernia (Italy)

Short Biography

Dario Di Nucci is a research fellow at the Software Languages Lab of the Vrije Universiteit Brussel in Belgium. He received a PhD in Management and Information Technology from the University of Salerno in 2018 advised by Prof. Andrea De Lucia with a thesis entitled "Methods and Tools for Focusing and Prioritizing the Testing Effort". His research interests are within Software Engineering and include software maintenance and evolution, software testing, search based software engineering, green mining, mining software repositories, and empirical software engineering.

Degrees

2014/12 – 2018/03 DOCTOR OF PHILOSOPHY (Ph.D.) IN MANAGEMENT & INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

University of Salerno, Italy

Fully funded by University of Salerno

Dissertation titled "Methods and Tools for Focusing and Prioritizing the Testing Effort" promoted by

professor Andrea De Lucia

2011/10 - 2014/09 MASTER'S DEGREE (M.Sc.) IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

University of Salerno, Italy 110/110 cum laude

Dissertation titled "A defect prediction model based on relationships between developers and modified

files" promoted by professor Andrea De Lucia

2007/10 – 2011/05 BACHELOR'S DEGREE (B.Sc.) IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

University of Molise, Italy 110/110 cum laude

Dissertation titled "Applications of mathematical models to semantic research" promoted by professor

Giovanni Capobianco

Employment History

Full Employment History

01-2019 - ACTUAL POST-DOCTORAL RESEARCHER

Vrije Universiteit Brussel, Belgium

FWO EOS project "SECO-ASSIST: Automated Assistance for Developing Software in Ecosystems of

the Future" (https://secoassist.github.io/)

12-2019 – ACTUAL POST-DOCTORAL LECTURER

Vrije Universiteit Brussel, Belgium Capita Selecta of Software Engineering

(elective course in first year Master's in Computer Science)

01/2018 - 12/2018 POST-DOCTORAL RESEARCHER

Vrije Universiteit Brussel, Belgium

Innoviris TeampUP project "INTiMALS INTelligent Modernisation Assistance for Legacy Software"

(http://soft.vub.ac.be/intimals/)

2014/12 - 2018/03 Ph.D. STUDENT IN MANAGEMENT & INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

University of Salerno, Italy

Fully funded by University of Salerno. Advisor: Prof. Andrea De Lucia

04/2014 - 09/2014 SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Gnome and GraphHopper Google Summer of Code 2014

09/2011 - 01/2012 SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CercAziende.it, Venafro, Italy

Development of a search engine for indexing and searching data on SQL databases

11/2005 - 12/2005 CUSTOMER SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE / TECHNICAL SUPPORT

eliquidMEDIA International Inc., Windsor, ON, Canada Web development and customer relationship handling

International Experience

2017/03 - 2017/05 VISITING STUDENT

Delft University of Technology, The Netherlands

Supervision: Prof. Andy Zaidman

2016/05 - 2016/07 VISITING STUDENT

Delft University of Technology, The Netherlands

Supervision: Prof. Andy Zaidman

2013/03 ERASMUS IP HUMAN-MACHINE INTERACTION

Reims, France

Teaching

CAPITA SELECTA OF SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Vrije Universiteit Brussel, Belgium (elective course in first year Master's in Computer Science) Co-holder of the course (holder: Prof. Coen De Roover) 2018-2019

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING, MANAGEMENT AND EVOLUTION

University of Salerno, Italy (mandatory course in first year Master's in Computer Science) Teaching assistant (holder: Prof. Andrea De Lucia) 2015-2016, 2016-2017

PROGRAMMING I

University of Salerno, Italy (mandatory course in first year Bachelor's in Computer Science) Teaching assistant

2016-2017 (holder: Prof. Riccardo Di Stasi) 2015-2016 (holder: Prof. Enrico Fischetti)

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

University of Salerno, Italy (mandatory course in third year

(mandatory course in third year Bachelor's in Computer Science)

Teaching assistant (holder: Prof. Andrea De Lucia)

2016-2017, 2015-2016

WEB DEVELOPMENT

University of Salerno, Italy (mandatory course in third year Bachelor's in Computer Science) Teaching assistant 2016-2017

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING: MAINTENANCE AND TESTING

University of Salerno, Italy

(mandatory course in first year Master's in Computer Science)

Teaching assistant (holder: Prof. Andrea De Lucia)

2015-2016

Publication Summary (since 2015)

Journal Articles: 4, Conference Papers: 8 (main track), 5 (tool demonstrations track), Workshop Papers: 4

Citations: 161, h-index: 9, https://scholar.google.it/citations?user=YJqcbnIAAAAJ&hl=it

Awards

2017 NSF TRAVEL SUPPORT

Symposium on Search-Based Software Engineering (SSBSE), Raleigh, NC, United States

2015 ACM SIGSOFT STUDENT TRAVEL GRANT

37th ACM/IEEE International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE), Florence, Italy

Recent Scientific Service

Organization of Summer Schools

2019 COMMITTEE MEMBER

14th International Summer School on Software Engineering, University of Salerno, Italy

2017 SCIENTIFIC SECRETARIAT

13th International Summer School on Software Engineering, University of Salerno, Italy

2016 SCIENTIFIC SECRETARIAT

12th International Summer School on Software Engineering, University of Salerno, Italy

Program Committee Member of International Conferences

2019 27th ACM Joint European Software Engineering Conference and Symposium on the Foundations of

Software Engineering (ESEC/FSE) – Artefact Evaluation Track

 6^{th} IEEE/ACM International Conference on Mobile Software Engineering and Systems (MOBILESoft) -

Student Research Competition

5th International Conference on Advances and Trends in Software Engineering (SOFTENG)

2018 34th IEEE International Conference on Software Maintenance and Evolution (ICSME) - Tool Demo Track

5th IEEE/ACM International Conference on Mobile Software Engineering and Systems (MOBILESoft) –

Student Research Competition

10th International Conference on Advances in System Testing and Validation Lifecycle (VALID)

2017 9th International Conference on Advances in System Testing and Validation Lifecycle (VALID)

Program Committee Member of International Workshops

2019 3rd Workshop on Machine Learning Techniques for Software Quality Evaluation (MaLTeSQuE)

2018 1st International Workshop on Cloud-Native Applications Design and Experience (CNAX)

2nd Workshop on Machine Learning Techniques for Software Quality Evaluation (MaLTeSQuE)

Editorial Board Member of International Journals

2019 - ACTUAL IEEE Software Blog

Reviewer

CONFERENCES

INTERNATIONAL Advances in Software Engineering - Elsevier

JOURNALS Arabian Journal for Science and Engineering – Springer

Computational Intelligence - Wiley Empirical Software Engineering - Springer

IEEE Access - IEEE

IET Software - Institution of Engineering and Technology

Information Processing Letters - Elsevier

Journal of King Saud University, Computer and Information Sciences - Elsevier

Journal of Software: Evolution and Process – Wiley Journal of Systems and Software – Elsevier Science of Computer Programming - Elsevier

Scientific Programming - Hidawi Software Quality Journal – Springer

Transactions on Knowledge and Data Engineering - IEEE

INTERNATIONAL IEEE International Conference on Software Analysis, Evolution, and Reengineering: 2017, 2018

IEEE International Conference on Program Comprehension: 2016, 2019

IEEE International Conference on Software Maintenance and Evolution: 2016 (ERA Track), 2018

International Conference on Business Information Systems: 2015, 2016 International Conference on Distributed Multimedia Systems: 2015, 2016 International Conference on Enterprise Information Systems: 2015, 2016, 2017

International Conference on Mining Software Repositories: 2019